

Curriculum Vitae

ASHWINI RAHUL PAWAR

Contact: +91 9860526572

E-mail: ashwinipawar77@gmail.com

ProfileSummary

HR professional with significant expertise and experience of 10+ Years in managing a wide spectrum of Human Resource Management functions entailing Generalist to Specialist in Hospital / Healthcare industry with a view to secure a sound Work Culture within the Organization.

Areas of Expertise

- Human Resources Strategic HR
- HR Audits/Accreditations
- Change Management
- Performance Management
- Reward & Recognition
- Training & Development

Compensation & Benefits

- **Employee Engagement**
- Recruitment
- **Statutory Compliances**
- Salary Negotiations
- General Administration

Work Experience

Deenanath Mangeshkar Hospital as Personnel Executive (February 2007 to June 2013)

Key Roles:

- ✓ Helping in setting up of KRAs/KPIs and Competencies
 ✓ Ensuring Correct & timely Pay roll inputs, Full & Final settlement of Employees with no Revenue leakage
- ✓ Timely Statutory fillings like PF, PT, MLWF, Annual Returns & others under various Acts
- ✓ Ensuring timely Performance Reviews and Roll out of Annual Increments, Promotions, Incentives &Bonus
- ✓ Organizations Capability Development by identifying Training & Development needs and ensuring training of Manpower as per Learning & Development Calendar
- ✓ Time Office
- ✓ Working on Scarcity Bonds of Nurses, Staff, Technicians etc.
- ✓ Preparing Organization Chart
- ✓ Event Management like Women's Day, Counseling sessions with Professional Counselors
- ✓ Involved in the documentation of Labour Union

<u>National Institute of Opthamology (NIO), Shivajinagar As an Assistant Manager – Human</u> Resource (July 2013 to June 2015)

- Overall management of employee compensation and benefits (Doctors, other hospital staff including paramedical, support and administration) and making sure they are compliant with applicable laws and regulations. Minimising statutory liability through proper salary structuring. Salary benchmarking. Manage payroll-related information (for example: new hires, adjustments, full and final settlements).
- ✓ Overall management of HR department and its functions.
- ✓ Recruitment, New employee Induction, Employee Life Cycle
- ✓ NABH related documentation and faced audits of NABH and JCI
- ✓ Time Office Management: Attendance and leave management through Saral Pay Pack
- ✓ Issuing offer letters, appointment orders, fixed term contracts, agreements, renewal of orders.
- ✓ Establish, update, and communicate workplace policies and procedures (for example: employee Induction Booklet and standard operating procedures) and monitor its application and enforcement to ensure consistency.
- ✓ Employee disciplinary actions: Issuing and tracking charge sheets, warning letters and other disciplinary actions for workplace misconducts.
- ✓ Manage exit/off-boarding process for both voluntary and involuntary employee terminations. Ensuring timely and complete full and final settlement.
- ✓ Employee Performance Management: Timely issuing appraisals, preparing reports, salary revision, promotion and issuing orders.
- ✓ Verifying employee credentials and employee background verification(Reference Check)
- ✓ Coordinating and organizing all training programs.

Colony Nursing Home(Sangamnerkar Hospitals) As Manager – Human Resource

(February 2016 to July 2021)

- ✓ Overall management of HR department and its functions.
- ✓ Recruitment, New employee Induction, Employee Life Cycle
- ✓ NABH related documentation and faced audits of NABH
- ✓ Played role of communicator(Coordinator) in NABH Process. From Application to NC Clearance
- ✓ Time Office Management: Attendance and leave management
- ✓ Issuing offer letters, appointment orders, fixed term contracts, agreements, renewal of orders.
- ✓ Establish, update, and communicate workplace policies and procedures (for example: employee Induction Manual and standard operating procedures) and monitor its application and enforcement to ensure consistency.
- ✓ Employee disciplinary actions: Issuing and tracking charge sheets, warning letters and other disciplinary actions for workplace misconducts.
- ✓ Manage exit/off-boarding process for both voluntary and involuntary employee terminations. Ensuring timely and complete full and final settlement.
- ✓ Employee Performance Management: Timely issuing appraisals, preparing reports, salary revision, promotion and issuing orders.
- ✓ Verifying employee credentials and employee background verification(Reference Check)

<u>Currently working in Oyster & Pearl Hospitals(ONP), Shivajinagar As Sr. Executive - Human Resources</u>

(February 2022 to till date)

- ✓ Recruitment through Advertisement, Naukri Portal, Indeed Portal, LinkedIn, Internal Reference etc.
- ✓ Salary Processing
- ✓ Budgeting of Employees,
- ✓ Statutory Compliances PF, PT, MLWF, Bonus, Minimum Wages etc.
- ✓ NABH related documentation and faced audits of NABH
- ✓ Employee disciplinary actions: Issuing and tracking charge sheets, warning letters and other disciplinary actions for workplace misconducts.
- ✓ Employee Performance Management: Timely issuing appraisals, preparing reports, salary revision, promotion and issuing orders.
- ✓ Issuing offer letters, appointment orders, Contracts agreements, Non Disclosure Agreements, renewal of orders.
- ✓ Establish, update, and communicate workplace policies and procedures and monitor its application and enforcement to ensure consistency.
- ✓ Induction Programme
- ✓ Arrange Various Training Programmes Internal and External
- ✓ Employee Engagement Activities
- ✓ Employee Life Cycle
- ✓ Spine Software Implementation

EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS

MPM(Mater in Personnel Management) (HR)

University of PUNE

Passed- 2005

BSc (Science)

University of PUNE

Passed- 2002-2003

PERSONAL DETAILS

DOB : 30-08-1980 Sex : Female Marital Status : Married

Address : B7, 703, Bhujbal Township, Kothrud, Pune

"I solemnly declare that the above particulars of facts and information stated are true, correct and complete to the best of my belief and knowledge."

Date:	Ashwini Agashe-Pawar
Location:	(Signature)